# Alejandro Munoz

0414 822 270

alej.munoz@protonmail.com

rtxd.github.io/

github.com/rtxd

# Career Objective

I am a final year Bachelor of Science in Information and Technology student. I have a passion for working closely in teams to develop software. I would love a position that allows me to develop the skills and experience I have received from university and apply them in a real work environment.

### **Technical Skills**

- C#, C++, Java, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, JavaScript
- Node JS, ReactJS, Redux, Express JS
- MySQL, MS SQL Express
- Experience using AWS to setup an RDS instance, S3 Bucket and EC2 instances
- Unity, MonoGame

### Education

#### 2017 - Present

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology and Diploma in Information Technology Professional Practice University of Technology Sydney

#### 2014

Certificate II in Information, Digital Media and Technology Academy of Interactive Entertainment

#### 2011 - 2016

Marcellin College Randwick

Received the Champagnat Award which is presented to students who are recognised as role models within the college community.

# **Employment History**

ReachOut Australia
August 2020 – Current
Front-end Developer (6-week volunteer role)

ReachOut Australia are a not-for-profit who support youth and young people going through a rough patch through to mental illness.

Working with their digital team, I've been re-creating some older components in new tech (TypeScript and React). These components will be used on ReachOut.com the primary site for ReachOut Australia.

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Building a social media sharing component in React JS using Typescript
- Writing styled components in React that can be re-used and are extensible
- Following best practices in ES6/Typescript
- Using Webpack for bundling and Yarn for package management
- Writing unit tests, going through code reviews with the Lead Developer
- Following CI/CD team practices/guidelines and Bitbucket (familiar with branching, pull requests etc)

Tech: React, Typescript, Webpack, Yarn, HTML5, CSS, Bitbucket (Git), Jira, Confluence

#### **PixateMe**

#### November 2019 – February 2020

#### Web Developer (full time position)

PixateMe is a Shopify site that sells Minecraft onesies. I was able to setup and design a complete Shopify store. This involved developing a small program in Node JS that gets a Minecraft skin and puts it onto a Onesie pattern read for printing.

Unfortunately, we didn't get this off the ground before COVID-19, however the Shopify site was well tested and had complete Stripe integration ready to go.

- Building a working Shopify site that included stripe payment
- Setup and designed a complete Shopify store: pixateme.com
- Developed a small program in Node JS that gets a Minecraft skin and puts it onto a Onesie pattern ready for printing.

Tech: JavaScript (ES6), Shopify

#### **Cloomein Pty Ltd**

#### September 2018 – February 2020

#### **Co-Founder of Cloomein (full-time role)**

Cloomein is a web application that keeps customers informed in real time. It helps businesses keep customers informed on the progress of the service that they're providing.

For example, a mechanic might have a standard workflow. Each time they get through an item (ie changing oil) they tick it off and Cloomein will generate a notification for the customer providing real-time progress of the workflow.

Targeted mostly at the Tourism industry, we had two tour guides using the beta version of the application and were seeking to get further feedback and make adaptions to our product/features moving forward.

Cloomein is a progressive web application built in React. Due to COVID-19 we decided to put our plans for Cloomein on hold.

#### **Key responsibilities:**

- Co-Founded Cloomein, a company that developed applications to help increase customer service for businesses and provide real time data on those services.
- Developed Cloomein, a progressive mobile web app in React (Redux) with Node JS, Express and MySQL
- Designed and developed responsive pages using Material UI's standards for styling and Google design documentation
- Created backend database and API Endpoints using Express
- Create Cloomein WordPress site: cloomein.com

#### SkyWriter Tech Pty Ltd June 2017 – July 2017

#### **Junior Software Developer**

SkyWriter Tech was a very small start-up company that was updating a legacy application and re-building this using a modern tech stack.

I was working on creating and fixing up tests and was involved in creating a proof of concept application that used DevExpress Technology (using .Net and C#) to generate an interactive report within a webpage.

#### WiseTech Global Pty. Ltd.

July 2014

Junior Dev (2 week - work experience role)

- Translogix Systems Transport Logistics Software
- Developed software written in C# and SQL which retrieved data from an external database, hosted on a server, and then displayed the data.

## **Extracurricular Activities**

#### Participated in University of New South Wales ProgComp

June 2014

#### **The Software Development Studio UTS**

July 2017 - October 2017

- Developed a web-based solution for the global company Ericsson
- Solution involved use google map APIs to create optimised routes for workers to follow and to allow data analysts to pick up any discrepancies in data easily.
- Team worked in Angular 1 to further develop the project and successfully met the requirements that were given to us.
- The project was worked on with two-week sprints on top of University classes and study.

#### Secretary of the Programmers' Society UTS

November 2017 - November 2018

Helped run and organise:

- WiseTech Global sponsored Hackathon
- Programming Competition
- VR Night
- Arduino workshop collaboration with other societies

## Transferable Skills

#### **Planning and Organisational Skills**

As the secretary of the Programmers' Society I had to Plan and Organise several events that we hosted. All these events were considered successful and raised the amount of memberships within the Programmers' Society.

#### **Teamwork**

My ability to collaborate and coordinate as a team. This has been demonstrated through my work in the Software Development Project subject which we had to work in small efficient teams of 5 to completely develop a piece of software. Also demonstrated through my role as secretary for the Programmers' Society.

#### Entrepreneurship

I have experience with setting up and running businesses. My first start-up company was a tech start-up by the name of Cloomein. I co-founded Cloomein with two other colleagues and worked on it for 2 years. The second start-up I worked on is called PixateMe, I had an idea that I thought might have a chance and took a shot.

### Referees

Available upon request